cornucopia.org 2019-11-17

# Cornucopia’s Privacy Policy - Cornucopia Institute

The Cornucopia Institute values your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes how we protect the privacy of website visitors and donors. This Policy also outlines how you can update your information or communication preferences and how you can receive additional information.

 **Protecting Donor Information**

Cornucopia uses electronic security systems to protect records containing personal identifying information that donors provide when giving a gift, whether online or off. This information is stored in a secure database that a limited number of staff have access to. We use this information to send donors eNews, action alerts, hardcopy newsletters, membership renewals and appeals, and other relevant communications throughout the year. If you would like to review your donor information or change your communications preferences, please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) Due to the controversial nature of our work, we never publish, share, sell, or otherwise distribute donor information, unless required to do so by law.

 **Online Giving**

All online donations to Cornucopia are processed by an integrated third-party vendor that specializes in secure donations (Blackbaud). Submissions are encrypted with Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, the industry standard for secure online transactions. All personal information, including credit card number, name, and address, is encrypted. All online transactions (whether one time or sustaining donations) are handled by a secure third-party donation management provider; Cornucopia staff do not have access to credit card information, nor is this information stored in our secure donor database. State laws require us to let online donors know how they can access financial information about The Cornucopia Institute. Please see the section below on State Disclosures for this information.

 **Visitors to our Website: Non-Personal Identifying Information**

Cornucopia collects and uses non-personal identifying information, including IP addresses and web server log files. We also uses cookies to identify individual computers accessing our website. Cornucopia uses this information only in the aggregate to gauge interest in our web content. We do not combine non-personal identifying information with personal identifying information, known as online profiling. At no time is personal information stored in a cookie.

Cornucopia shares a summary of non-identifying aggregated information about website usage with funders to show the impact of our communications work. For example, we may share with our donors or a foundation that 100,000 people visited the carrageenan scorecard last year.

 **Personal Identifying Information**

If you voluntarily provide personal identifying information (such as name, address, e-mail address) through online or hardcopy forms, Cornucopia will collect and retain this information to fulfill the related request. For example, if you subscribe to our eNews, your name and e-mail address will be stored so that we can send you the eNews regularly until you unsubscribe.

Cornucopia makes this personal identifying information available to other organizations only when this is made explicit on the collection form. For instance, when you fill out a proxy letter or sign a petition, the information you provide is transmitted to the government agency targeted for that action.

In addition, Cornucopia may share information with business partners in order to execute a requested service. For example, Cornucopia may use a third-party vendor (like Constant Contact) to distribute the eNews, which requires sharing email addresses with that vendor. We only partner with vendors who respect our privacy terms.

 **E-mail Communications**

Cornucopia sends out bi-weekly eNews, periodic action alerts, and other mission and development related communications via email to interested parties. These communications are intended to be relevant. If you wish to unsubscribe, all group emails offer an easy unsubscribe option at the bottom of the message. In the unlikely event that you have unsubscribed and are still receiving emails, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or call us on 608-625-2000 to be manually removed from future email communications.

 **Links**

Cornucopia’s website contains links to other sites. Cornucopia does not control, and is not responsible for, the privacy policies of those other sites. When clicking on a link from the Cornucopia website, please make yourself aware of that site’s privacy policy.

 **Google Services**

Cornucopia uses Google Analytics Demographics for website use analysis, which provides us reports on the aggregate age, gender and interests of site visitors. We do not obtain, store or otherwise have access to personal information about individual website visitors.

Cornucopia uses Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online to visitors who have come to our site. This tailored advertising is enabled by the Google Analytics cookie and the DoubleClick cookie. Google and other third-party vendors may show Cornucopia ads on sites across the Internet to visitors with these or other, similar, Cornucopia remarketing cookies.

You can use Google’s Ads’ Settings to opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising or customize Google Display Network ads to your interests.

 **Protecting Children’s Privacy**

In an effort to comply voluntarily with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, Cornucopia does not knowingly collect and retain personal identifying information from children under the age of 13. We urge children to talk with their parents before entering any personal information in Cornucopia web forms. If Cornucopia learns that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13 without parental consent, we will delete that information. 

**State Disclosures**

The Cornucopia Institute knows that good stewardship is important! In keeping with state guidelines, we want to tell you the following. Financial and other information about The Cornucopia Institute’s purpose, programs and activities can be obtained by contacting Will Fantle at P.O Box 126, Cornucopia, WI 54827, or for residents of the following states, as stated below. **Florida** : SC No. CH46228 A COPY OF THE OFFICIAL REGISTRATION AND FINANCIAL INFORMATION MAY BE OBTAINED FROM THE DIVISION OF CONSUMER SERVICES BY CALLING TOLL-FREE, WITHIN THE STATE, 1-800-HELP-FLA OR VIA THE INTERNET AT [WWW.800HELPFLA.COM](http://www.800helpfla.com/). **Maryland** : For the cost of postage and copying, from the Secretary of State. **Michigan** : MICS No. 54067 **Mississippi** : The official registration and financial information of The Cornucopia Institute may be obtained from the Mississippi Secretary of State’s office by calling 1-888-236-6167. **Nevada** : The state of incorporation of The Cornucopia Institute is Wisconsin. **New Jersey** : INFORMATION FILED WITH THE ATTORNEY GENERAL CONCERNING THIS CHARITABLE SOLICITATION AND THE PERCENTAGE OF CONTRIBUTIONS RECEIVED BY THE CHARITY DURING THE LAST REPORTING PERIOD THAT WERE DEDICATED TO THE CHARITABLE PURPOSE MAY BE OBTAINED FROM THE ATTORNEY GENERAL OF THE STATE OF NEW JERSEY BY CALLING (973) 504- 6215 AND IS AVAILABLE ON THE INTERNET AT <http://www.state.nj.us/lps/ca/charfrm.htm>. **New York** : **Upon request, from the Attorney General Charities Bureau, 120 Broadway, New York, NY 10271.** **North Carolina** : _Financial information about this organization and a copy of its license are available from the State Solicitation Licensing Branch at 1-888-830-4989 (within North Carolina) or (919) 807-2214 (outside of North Carolina)_. **Pennsylvania** : The official registration and financial information of The Cornucopia Institute may be obtained from the Pennsylvania Department of State by calling toll-free, within Pennsylvania, 1-800-732-0999. **Virginia** : From the State Office of Consumer Affairs in the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Affairs, P.O. Box 1163, Richmond, VA 23218. **Washington** : From the Secretary of State at 1-800- 332-4483. **West Virginia** : West Virginia residents may obtain a summary of the registration and financial documents from the Secretary of State, State Capitol, Charleston, WV 25305. CONTRIBUTIONS ARE DEDUCTIBLE FOR FEDERAL INCOME TAX PURPOSES IN ACCORDANCE WITH APPLICABLE LAW. REGISTRATION IN A STATE DOES NOT IMPLY ENDORSEMENT, APPROVAL, OR RECOMMENDATION OF THE CORNUCOPIA INSTITUTE BY THE STATE.

 **Contact For More Information**

Please contact us to view or update your information, to change communication preferences, for help unsubscribing to group emails, or for any other privacy related matter.

The Cornucopia Institute  
P.O. Box 826  
Viroqua, WI 54665  
Phone: 608-637-8278  
Email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4023352c34293621342500232f322e23352f3029216e2f3227)

In the event that this Privacy Policy changes, Cornucopia will post updates on this page.
